Arsenii Ashukha

Home page / Google Scholar / GitHub / Twitter /

↑ London (UK, GT visa) / E-mail: ars.ashuha@gmail.com

I am a Senior Research Scientist at Isomorphic Labs, Alphabet subsidiary led by Demis Hassabis, where I develop and train deep learning models for drug descovery. Prior to joining Iso, I recived PhD in machine learning. You might have come across the following projects I worked on: github.com/advimman/lama, github.com/SamsungLabs/pytorch-ensembles, github.com/bayesgroup/variational-dropout-sparsifies-dnn.

Publications scholar.google.com/citations?user=IU-kuP8AAAA

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2022 - now	Isomorphic Labs Senior Research Scientist (Feb 2024). Research Scientist (Oct 2022). Stealth models for drug design.
2018 - 2022	Samsung AI Research Scientist (PhD student equivalent). Uncertainty, generative models. Published a range of ICLR/NeurIPS papers. Develop models that are used in the real world (e.g. <u>LaMa inpainting</u>).
2016 - 2018	National Research University Higher School of Economics Research Scientist (PhD student equivalent). Created sparse variational dropout, over 250x compression ratio (ICML'17).
Internships	2016 Yandex Deep learning based recommendation system for spotify-like music service.2015 Rambler Language models based recommendation systems for news aggregators.
EDUCATION	
2017 - 2022	PhD in Machine Learning, National Research University Higher School of Economics Title: Prior Knowledge for Deep Learning (<u>link</u>). Advisor: Dmitry Vetrov. Committee: Durk Kingma, Karen Ullrich, Jasper Snoek, Yingzhen Li, Sergey Nikolenko.
2015 - 2017	MSc in Computer Science, Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology with Distinction
2011 - 2015	BSc in Computer Science, Bauman Moscow State Technical University

MISCELLANEOUS

- **Technical stack:** deep learning, deep neural networks, machine learning, python, numpy, matplotlib, scikit-learn, pandas, bash, git, linux, jax, pytorch, distributed training, dataflow, beam.
- Code: Research-ready implementations: LaMa Image Inpainting (★8.4k), Multi-GPU SimCLRv1, Ensembles. Simple
 MVP implementations of ML algorithms: Real NVP normalizing flows, Quantile Regression DQN (Distributional RL),
 Equivariant GNN
- Programm committee: NeurIPS 2021: outstanding reviewer award, ICML 2020 top-33% highest-scored reviewers
- Thesis co-supervision: Alexander Lyzhov (moved to NYU, Deep Ensembles: Analysis and Approaches to Diversification MSc, 2020), Andrei Atanov (moved to EPFL, Effective Learning of Deep Neural Networks Ensembles BSc, 2018, Learning Deep Models with Small Data MSc, 2020), Evgenii Nikishin (moved to Mila, Stability Improvement and Knowledge Transfer in Deep Reinforcement Learning MSc, 2019).